# **Baoqian Wang**

\$\square\$ 9797396050 | \square\$ bawang@ucsd.edu | Personal Website

### **SUMMARY**

I am a third year Ph.D. student in the joint doctoral program between University of California San Diego and San Diego State University. My research interests include robotics sensing, estimation, planning and learning, cyber physical systems, and distributed computing.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of California San Diego San Diego State University

Aug. 2019 - Dec. 2022

San Diego, CA

Joint Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering; Overall GPA: 3.83/4

• Coursework at UCSD: Convex Optimization; Search and Optimization; Robotics Sensing&Estimation; Robotics Planning&Learning; Robot Reinforcement Learning

## **Texas A&M University Corpus Christi**

Aug. 2017 - May 2019

Corpus Christi, TX

M.S. in Computer Science; Overall GPA: 3.82/4

• Coursework: Statistic Learning, Design and Analysis of Algorithms; Data Structures; Advanced Operating Systems; Advanced Computer Architecture; Mobile Software Development; Spatial Statistics

#### **Yangtze University**

Aug. 2013 – May 2017

B.S. in Prospecting Technology and Engineering; Overall GPA: 3.9/4

Wuhan, China

• Coursework: Advanced Mathematics; Linear Algebra; Probability Theory; C Programming; Matlab Programming;

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming languages**: Python (tensorflow, pytorch, mpi4py, etc.), C/C++, Matlab, Android Java, Latex, HTML **Tools**: Github, AWS, ROS, Matlab Simulink, Docker, KVM, Android Studio.

#### **ACADEMIC WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### San Diego State University

Research Assistant

Dec. 2020 - Present

San Diego, CA

- Conduct researches on Distributed Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning under guidance of Prof. Nikolay Atanasov from UCSD and Prof.Junfei Xie from SDSU. Have one paper published and one paper submitted to the top tier conferences in the area of robotics (ICRA) and AI (AAAI), respectively.
- Conduct researches on Towards Networked Airborne Computing in Uncertain Airspace and published one journal and several conference papers in the area of communications such as ICC, Globecom, TNSE.
- Serve as an advisor for Master and Undergraduate students in the lab, for instance, participated in an undergraduate student competition as an advisor in 2020 IEEE/ASME International Conference on Advanced Intelligent Mechatronics (AIM) and won Special Track on Networked Computing on the Edge Award.

## San Diego State University

Teaching Assistant

Aug. 2019 - Dec. 2020

San Diego, CA

• Taught two lectures and graded assignments, projects, exams for the course **EE600 Seminar: Machine Learning**.

**Texas A&M University Corpus Christi** 

Sept. 2017 – Aug. 2019

Research Assistant

Corpus Christi, TX

- Conduct researches on Developing an Open Networked Airborne Computing Platform and published one journal and several conference papers in the area of unmanned aerial systems (ICUAS), and communications (IET Communications).
- Conduct researches on Hybrid Deep Learning-based and Physical Model-based Trajectory Modeling for UAVs and published one conference paper in AIAA Scitech.
- Implement algorithms from research papers on real robotics systems such as vision-based object tracking and localization of a mobile robot.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Distributed Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning**

Mar. 2020 - present

Collaborative project between UCSD and SDSU funded by NSF and DCIST

- Distributed training framework to improve the training efficiency of multi-agent reinforcement learning.
- Coded scheme to improve robustness of the distributed training system to uncertain stragglers.

## **Vision-based Autonomous Driving Robot**

Feb. 2020 - May 2020

Undergraduate student competition in 2021 IEEE/ASME AIM.

 An autonomous driving robot that is capable of navigating in both a known urban environment and an unknown and dynamic rural environment, which is achieved by deep reinforcement learning.

## **Towards Networked Airborne Computing**

Sept. 2019 – present

NSF CAREER funded project

- · Mobility-aware coded distributed computing.
- Stochastic mobility control to facilitate robust computing under uncertainty.

## **Develop an Open Networked Airborne Computing Platform**

Sept. 2017 - Sept. 2019

NSF funded project

- A platform using Jetson TX2 as computing unit, and directional antenna to enable long range communication.
- Implementation of two virtualization techniques including Docker and KVM on Jetson TX2 to improve computing capability.

## **Trajectory Modeling for UAVs**

Sept. 2017 - Sept. 2019

NSF EAGER funded project

- A comprehensive 3-D mobility model to capture the movements of aircrafts.
- Combination of deep Learning-based model (LSTM) and UAV physical model for trajectory modeling.

#### **Geolocation Using Video Sensor Measurements**

Feb. 2019 - Jun. 2019

- Visioned-based objecting tracking of mobile robot using YoloV3.
- Mobile robot localization with camera projection model.

## **AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS**

SDSU Graduate Fellowship (\$25,000)

Jun. 2021

SDSU Graduate Travel Fund (\$1000)

Oct. 2020

President's International Excellence Scholarship (\$3000)

Sept. 2018

The first class scholarship for international students in Texas A&M University Corpus Christi

National Scholarship (¥8000)

Oct. 2016

A scholarship given to top 1% students in each university in China for their great academic performance.

Wang Tao Talent Scholarship (¥10000)

Oct. 2015

China National Petroleum Corporation Scholarship (¥6000)

Oct. 2014

#### **Publications**

#### **Journals**

- **B. Wang**, J. Xie, K. Lu, Y. Wan, S. Fu, "On Batch-Processing Based Coded Computing for Heterogeneous Distributed Computing Systems", **IEEE Transactions on Network Science and Engineering**, Vol.8, pp:2438-2454, 2021.
- B. Wang, J. Xie, S. Li, Y. Wan, Y. Gu, S. Fu, K. Lu, "Computing in the Air: An Open Airborne Computing Platform", IET Communications, Vol.14, pp. 2410-2419, 2020.
- J. Xie, Y. Wan, **B. Wang**, S. Fu, K. Lu, "A Comprehensive 3-Dimensional Random Mobility Modeling Framework for Airborne Networks", **IEEE Access**, Vol.6, pp. 22849-22862, 2018.

#### **Conferences**

- D. Wang, B. Wang, J. Zhang, K. Lu, J. Xie, Y. Wan, S. Fu, "CFL-HC: A Coded Federated Learning Framework for Heterogeneous Computing Scenarios", 2021 IEEE Global Communications Conference (Globecom).
- B. Wang, J. Xie, N. Atanasov, "Coding for Distributed Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning", 2021 International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA).
- B. Wang, J. Xie, K. Lu, Y. Wan, S. Fu "Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning Based Coded Computation for Mobile Ad Hoc Computing", 2021 International Conference on Communications (ICC).
- C. Douma, B. Wang, "Coded Distributed Path Planning for Unmanned Aerial Vehicles", 2021 AIAA Aviation Forum
- B. Wang, J. Xie, "Data-Driven Multi-UAV Navigation in Large-ScaleDynamic Environment Under Wind Disturbances", 2021 AIAA Scitech Forum.
- B. Wang, J. Xie, Y. Wan, G. A. G. Reyes, L. R. G. Carrilo, "3-D Trajectory Modeling for Unmanned Aerial Vehicles", 2019 AIAA Scitech Forum.
- B. Wang, J. Xie, K. Lu, Y. Wan, "Coding for Heterogeneous UAV-based Networked Airborne Computing", 2019 IEEE Globecom Workshop.
- B. Wang, J. Xie, S. Li, Y. Wan, S. Fu, K. Lu, "Enabling High-Performance Onboard Computing with Virtualization for Unmanned Aerial Systems", 2018 International Conference on Unmanned Aircraft Systems (ICUAS).